Franco Waisfeld

<u>francowaisfeld@gmail.com</u> ((858)-886-6835

in /in/franco-waisfeld

/francowaisfeld

https://francowaisfeld.com

Combining my experience as a Founder and Full Stack Software Engineer specializing in the Node.js and React ecosystem, I bring a unique perspective to tech companies. I excel at creating products that drive customer retention while balancing business priorities and engineering decisions. My background enables me to bridge the gap between technical requirements and customer demands, resulting in scalable applications that users want.

Skills

Backend

Node.js, Express, Go, Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, REST APIs

Cloud

AWS (EC2, S3, Lambdas), Cloudflare (workers, Durable Objects), Digital Ocean, Heroku, fly.io

Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, React Native, jQuery, Handlebars.js, Tailwind, HTML, CSS

Other

Git / Github, bash, HTTP, WebSockets, Jest, OOP, Nginx, **Postman**

Experience

Software Engineer, Syncosaurus - framework for real-time collaborative applications

Jan 2024 - present

- · Designed and implemented a multi-client syncing system to enable real-time and collaborative features including delta updates, optimistic UI updates, adaptable conflict resolution, and batching.
- Developed a syncing system that supports shared state between up to ~50 clients through WebSocket Connections. (React, JavaScript, Node.js)
- · Researched tradeoffs of system architectures before building a backend consisting of Cloudflare edge workers and durable objects to support concurrent WebSocket connections and long-term persistent state storage. (JavaScript, Cloudflare Workers, Durable Objects, Websockets)
- · Worked with a remote team of 4 engineers through daily standups, pair programming, and code reviews. (Git, GitHub)

Software Engineer, Reveler - a ticket marketplace for nightlife venues

Aug 2022 - Sep 2023

- · Implemented key features on the web Next.js application, enabling users to purchase, use, and manage their tickets (Next.js)
- Developed an admin dashboard for venue managers to log in, manage ticket offerings, and ensure real-time updates (Next.js)
- Interviewed customers and prospects to create product roadmap

Software Engineer, Open-source projects

May 2022 - Jan 2024

- Webhook Gravity Well Tool for receiving, testing, and debugging webhooks. (React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Digital Ocean Droplet,
- smartCart eCommerce shopping cart. (React, Express, Node.js, MongoDB)
- Todo List Application for managing todo lists. (Ruby, Sinatra, ERB, PostgreSQL)

Marketing Strategist, The Hire Talent - SaaS for hiring better employees

Sep 2019 - Jan 2021

- Increased sales qualified leads by 72% as the only full-time marketing employee.
- Managed ad spend of \$20,000 a month across Google Search, LinkedIn, and Facebook.
- Rewrote copy for the entire website, resulting in a 31% increase in conversion rates.

Founder, Nova Crate - ecommerce store in the Household products niche

Mar 2018 - Aug 2019

- Scaled to \$30,000 a month in revenue
- · Managed ad spend of over \$10,000 a month
- Converted 4.2% of website visitors into buyers

Education

Launch School &